<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>KubeCon on Edenmal</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/tags/KubeCon/</link><description>Recent content in KubeCon on Edenmal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© This page/post is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License, please give source if you wish to quote or reproduce.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 15:50:42 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://edenmal.moe/tags/KubeCon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Distributed Storage with Rook Presentation</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/Distributed-Storage-with-Rook-Presentation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 15:50:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/Distributed-Storage-with-Rook-Presentation/</guid><description>Thanks! A thanks to Kim-Norman Sahm from Cloudical for reaching out to me if I wanted to talk about Rook with him. Also thanks to Jared Watts, Tony Allen and the other awesome Rook people for creating the slides for KubeCon Copenhagen 2018, on which we based our slides partially on.
Presentation Kim-Norman Sahm and I created this presentation to show off Rook.io at Container Days Hamburg. The files used in the demo during the presentation can be found here: GitHub galexrt/presentation-distributed-storage-with-rook.</description></item><item><title>KubeCon Copenhagen 2018 - Day 3</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/KubeCon-Copenhagen-2018-Day-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 08:16:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/KubeCon-Copenhagen-2018-Day-3/</guid><description>NOTE All credit for the slides in the pictures goes to their creators!
NOTE If you are in one of these pictures and want it removed, please contact me by email (see about/imprint page).
WIP This post is still work in progress! The content of this post can rapidly change. This note will be removed when the post has been completed. TODO
Proof read. Welcome! A warm &amp;ldquo;Welcome&amp;rdquo; if you are new to the three day post series from KubeCon Copenhagen, I recommend you to checkout the first day blog post too, here KubeCon Copenhagen 2018 Day 1 and the second day blog post, here KubeCon Copenhagen 2018 Day 2.</description></item><item><title>KubeCon Copenhagen 2018 - Day 2</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/KubeCon-Copenhagen-2018-Day-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 08:30:27 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/KubeCon-Copenhagen-2018-Day-2/</guid><description>NOTE
All credit for the slides in the pictures goes to their creators!
NOTE
If you are in one of these pictures and want it removed, please contact me by email (see about/imprint page).
WIP This post is still work in progress! The content of this post can rapidly change. This note will be removed when the post has been completed.
Welcome! A warm &amp;ldquo;Welcome&amp;rdquo; if you are new to the three day post series from KubeCon Copenhagen, I recommend you to checkout the first day blog post too, here KubeCon Copenhagen 2018 Day 1.</description></item><item><title>KubeCon Copenhagen 2018 - Day 1</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/KubeCon-Copenhagen-2018-Day-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 07:45:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/KubeCon-Copenhagen-2018-Day-1/</guid><description>NOTE
All credit for the slides in the pictures goes to their creators!
NOTE
If you are in one of these pictures and want it removed, please contact me by email (see about/imprint page).
WIP This post is still work in progress! The content of this post can rapidly change. This note will be removed when the post has been completed.
Welcome! A big welcome to everyone at KubeCon! I&amp;rsquo;m happy to have already met a good amount of Rooklers just during badge pickup.</description></item><item><title>KubeCon Austin 2017 (Recap) Presentation</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/KubeCon-Austin-2017-Recap-Presentation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 08:30:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/KubeCon-Austin-2017-Recap-Presentation/</guid><description>I created this presentation to recap my visit to KubeCon 2017 in Austin for my colleagues.
If you want to present my slides somewhere, please get in contact with me first. Thanks!
If you have any suggestions for the presentation, feel free to leave them in the comments. :)</description></item><item><title>KubeCon 2017 Austin</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/KubeCon-2017-Austin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 12:09:28 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/KubeCon-2017-Austin/</guid><description>NOTE All credit for the slides in the pictures goes to their creators!
NOTE If you are in one of these pictures and want it removed, please contact me by email (see about/imprint page).
Thanks! A huge thanks goes out to Rook and Quantum Corporation for helping me with my trip and the conference! Checkout their Twitter @rook_io and @QuantumCorp.
Day #0 NOTE If you don&amp;rsquo;t want to read about my flight and stay, skip to Day #1.</description></item></channel></rss>