<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Edenmal</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/</link><description>Recent content on Edenmal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© This page/post is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License, please give source if you wish to quote or reproduce.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 13:12:30 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://edenmal.moe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Taking Control</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2022/taking-control/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 13:12:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2022/taking-control/</guid><description>Just as a YouTuber would say now &amp;ldquo;Well.. it has been some time since my last video&amp;rdquo; and showing a screenshot of their last video&amp;rsquo;s upload time with the typical &amp;ldquo;it has been x weeks&amp;rdquo; or longer. Would it be wrong to do the same but with my last blog post?
Last blog article was from January 2020 Well.. it has been quite some time since my last blog post, hasn&amp;rsquo;t it?</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM'20 Brussels</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2020/FOSDEM20/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 19:06:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2020/FOSDEM20/</guid><description>Checkout the original publication of this article on the The Cloud Report site, where it was posted originally, here: The Cloud Report - FOSDEM’2020 Brussels.
Thanks to The Cloud Report for allowing me to write and publish the post on their blog!
I&amp;rsquo;m sitting in the ICE train back home from FOSDEM'2020 Brussels, and I’ve got only one thing to say: &amp;ldquo;What a wonderful weekend!&amp;rdquo;
FOSDEM, a weekend in Brussles, Belgium, where great minds in the form of developers, administrators and engineers meet and connect.</description></item><item><title>My Home Office Setup v2</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2020/My-Home-Office-Setup-v2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 11:58:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2020/My-Home-Office-Setup-v2/</guid><description>It was time Time to create an updated post of my improved home office setup. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive right into it.
Table The table is 1.60m (~5.24934 feet) long.
The cable management has been improved in comparsion to my previous setup post. It can still be further improved but it is much better than before and I&amp;rsquo;m finally happy with it now.
Table / Desk Shot Computers Gaming This compliments my &amp;ldquo;small&amp;rdquo; Steam library pretty well and the Valve Index headset which is pretty dope to use and play games on.</description></item><item><title>Rook: New Winds in the v1.1 release</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2020/Rook-New-Winds-in-the-v1-1-release/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 15:20:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2020/Rook-New-Winds-in-the-v1-1-release/</guid><description>This is a cross post of an older post from The Cloud Report, be sure to checkout the The Cloud Report website.
Thanks to them for allowing me to write and publish the post on their blog!
Preface Rook is a storage orchestrator for Kubernetes using the operator pattern. That means that Rook can run, e.g., Ceph, EdgeFS, Yugabyte and other persistence providers in a Kubernetes cluster. This allows applications to create, e.</description></item><item><title>Running ownCloud in Kubernetes with Rook Ceph Storage - Part 2</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2020/Running-ownCloud-in-Kubernetes-with-Rook-Ceph-Storage-Part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 14:56:41 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2020/Running-ownCloud-in-Kubernetes-with-Rook-Ceph-Storage-Part-2/</guid><description>This a cross post of a post I wrote for the ownCloud Blog, the original post can be found here: Running ownCloud in Kubernetes With Rook Ceph Storage – Step by Step.
Thanks to them for allowing me to write and publish the post on their blog!
Preparations Let&amp;rsquo;s prepare for the Kubernetes madness!
Kubernetes Cluster Access As written in the first part, it is expected that you have (admin) access to a Kubernetes cluster already.</description></item><item><title>Running ownCloud in Kubernetes with Rook Ceph Storage - Part 1</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2020/Running-ownCloud-in-Kubernetes-with-Rook-Ceph-Storage-Part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 14:55:41 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2020/Running-ownCloud-in-Kubernetes-with-Rook-Ceph-Storage-Part-1/</guid><description>This a cross post of a post I wrote for the ownCloud Blog, the original post can be found here: Running ownCloud in Kubernetes With Rook Ceph Storage.
Thanks to them for allowing me to write and publish the post on their blog!
In dieser zweiteiligen Artikelreihe wird es darum gehen ownCloud hochverfügbar in Kubernetes zu betreiben.
Der erste Teil wird dabei auf die Grundaspekte und Requirements eingehen, so das am Ende ein Plan bereit ist der im zweiten Teil dann Schritt für Schritt umgesetzt wird.</description></item><item><title>Ancientt - Automation for Network Testing Tools</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Ancientt-Automation-for-Network-Testing-Tools/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 13:10:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Ancientt-Automation-for-Network-Testing-Tools/</guid><description>This is a cross post from The Cloud Report. Be sure to checkout the The Cloud Report website.
What is Ancientt Ancientt is a tool to automate network testing tools, like iperf3, in dynamic environments such as Kubernetes, Ansible and more to come dynamic environments.
Meaning that, if you want to test the network throughput with iperf3 of your Kubernetes cluster, you can easily do that with Ancientt. A simple &amp;ldquo;test definitions&amp;rdquo; file is used to tell Ancientt what exactly to do:</description></item><item><title>Sitrep Container and IPv6 Presentation</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Sitrep-Container-and-IPv6-Presentation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 20:23:04 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Sitrep-Container-and-IPv6-Presentation/</guid><description>I created this presentation for a local IPv6 &amp;ldquo;Stammtisch&amp;rdquo; to talk about the current situation of IPv6 in Docker and Kubernetes.
If you want to present these slides somewhere, please get in contact with me first. Thanks!
If you have any suggestions for the presentation, feel free to leave them in the comments.</description></item><item><title>Importance of IPv6 in a Cloudy World Presentation</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Importance-of-IPv6-in-a-cloudy-World-Presentation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 12:50:19 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Importance-of-IPv6-in-a-cloudy-World-Presentation/</guid><description>I created this presentation to show off why IPv6 is important in the current day and age of Cloud at Container Days Hamburg.
If you want to present these slides somewhere, please get in contact with me first. Thanks!
If you have any suggestions for the presentation, feel free to leave them in the comments.
Recording The recording of the talk can be found on Container Days YouTube channel:
Impressions Good morning #containerdays</description></item><item><title>Matrix Synapse SAML2 Login</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Matrix-Synapse-SAML2-Login/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 11:51:19 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Matrix-Synapse-SAML2-Login/</guid><description>NOTE
This is a very rough write-up on how to use Keycloak SAML2 with a Matrix Synapse Homeserver for user authentication. Keep in mind that not all points outlined here may 100% work for you and &amp;ldquo;turning and changing&amp;rdquo; some parameters may be needed to get it working for your setup.
Intro This blog post is especially made for Keycloak SAML 2.0 SSO with Matrix with the GitHub matrix-org/synapse - Complete the SAML2 implementation #5422, which is based on my draft PR GitHub matrix-org/synapse - SAML2 Improvements and redirect stuff #5316.</description></item><item><title>GitLab + Kubernetes: Using GitLab CI's Kubernetes Cluster feature - UPDATED</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/GitLab-Kubernetes-Using-GitLab-CIs-Kubernetes-Cluster-feature/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 14:53:20 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/GitLab-Kubernetes-Using-GitLab-CIs-Kubernetes-Cluster-feature/</guid><description>Intro This post walks through using GitLab CI&amp;rsquo;s Kubernetes Cluster feature to deploy built container images to Kubernetes.
This is an update to my old guide which uses the in GitLab 10.3 deprecated Kubernetes integration feature, see: GitLab + Kubernetes: Perfect Match for Continuous Delivery with Container.
NOTE
Please check the requirements before beginning.
Requirements Kubernetes Cluster GitLab instance GitLab Container Registry enabled. GitLab CI runner configured and enabled. The CI runners must be able to access the Kubernetes apiserver.</description></item><item><title>Container and Kubernetes Training</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Container-and-Kubernetes-Training/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 22:20:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Container-and-Kubernetes-Training/</guid><description>Welcome! Quick short introduction to myself, my name is Alexander Trost. I’m a sysadmin who loves automation, containers, coding in Go, playing games but also with new technologies. I&amp;rsquo;m currently working at Cloudical as a DevOps Engineer, helping companies move to the cloud and / or to container technologies (e.g., Docker, Kubernetes, etc).
Goal of the Training The training is going to show how simple it is to get started with containers.</description></item><item><title>Container and Kubernetes - Day #3</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Container-and-Kubernetes-Training-Day3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 21:27:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Container-and-Kubernetes-Training-Day3/</guid><description>Welcome! Quick short introduction to myself, my name is Alexander Trost. I’m a sysadmin who loves automation, containers, coding in Go, playing games but also with new technologies. I&amp;rsquo;m currently working at Cloudical as a DevOps Engineer, helping companies move to the cloud and / or to container technologies (e.g., Docker, Kubernetes, etc).
Goal of the Training The training is going to show how simple it is to get started with containers.</description></item><item><title>Container and Kubernetes - Day #2</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Container-and-Kubernetes-Training-Day2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 21:25:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Container-and-Kubernetes-Training-Day2/</guid><description>Welcome! Quick short introduction to myself, my name is Alexander Trost. I’m a sysadmin who loves automation, containers, coding in Go, playing games but also with new technologies. I&amp;rsquo;m currently working at Cloudical as a DevOps Engineer, helping companies move to the cloud and / or to container technologies (e.g., Docker, Kubernetes, etc).
Goal of the Training The training is going to show how simple it is to get started with containers.</description></item><item><title>Container and Kubernetes - Day #1</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Container-and-Kubernetes-Training-Day1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 21:20:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Container-and-Kubernetes-Training-Day1/</guid><description>Welcome! Quick short introduction to myself, my name is Alexander Trost. I’m a sysadmin who loves automation, containers, coding in Go, playing games but also with new technologies. I&amp;rsquo;m currently working at Cloudical as a DevOps Engineer, helping companies move to the cloud and / or to container technologies (e.g., Docker, Kubernetes, etc).
Goal of the Training The training is going to show how simple it is to get started with containers.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM'19 Brussels</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/FOSDEM19-Brussels/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 17:50:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/FOSDEM19-Brussels/</guid><description>FOSDEM was from Saturday, 02.02. to Sunday, 03.02.2019 in Brussels, Belgium.
Saturday FOSDEM&amp;#39;19 Brussels - Snow on Saturday FOSDEM&amp;#39;19 Brussels - ULB FOSDEM middle &amp;#39;street&amp;#39; with food trucks FOSDEM&amp;#39;19 Brussels - Booth area FOSDEM&amp;#39;19 Brussels - Gluster, Ceph and Rook booth FOSDEM&amp;#39;19 Brussels - openSUSE Original &amp;#39;Tumbleweed&amp;#39; Beer Extra The Belgian know how to make freaking awesome waffles! LOOK AT THOSE WAFFLES!!!
FOSDEM&amp;#39;19 Brussels - Le Funambule Waffle Selection If you are in Brussels, go to Le Funambule in the inner city of Brussels:</description></item><item><title>My Sysctl Parameters</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/My-sysctl-Parameters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 08:15:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/My-sysctl-Parameters/</guid><description>These are the sysctl settings I deploy on most of my machines. The &amp;ldquo;machines&amp;rdquo; I am speaking of here, are &amp;ldquo;always&amp;rdquo; assumed to have at least the following &amp;ldquo;hardware&amp;rdquo; (it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t really matter if it is actual metal or virtual machine):
CPU: Quad or more Core RAM: 32GB or more memory Network: 1Gbit/s NOTE
For &amp;ldquo;thiccer wires&amp;rdquo;, one does simply increase the net.*mem parameters.
NOTE
I&amp;rsquo;m using parts of these paramters for machines smaller than the given &amp;ldquo;specs&amp;rdquo; too, but then modified a bit accordingly.</description></item><item><title>Rook more than Ceph</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Rook-more-than-Ceph/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 08:13:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Rook-more-than-Ceph/</guid><description>Checkout the orignal publication of this article on the The Cloud Report site here: The Cloud Report - Rook more than Ceph.
Preface Rook allows you to run Ceph and other storage backends in Kubernetes with ease. Consumption of storage, especially block and filesystem storage, can be consumed through Kubernetes native ways. this allows users of a Kubernetes cluster to consume storage easily as in &amp;ldquo;any&amp;rdquo; other standard Kubernetes cluster out there.</description></item><item><title>Ceph Day Berlin 2018</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/Ceph-Day-Berlin-2018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 08:00:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/Ceph-Day-Berlin-2018/</guid><description>NOTE
All credit for the slides in the pictures goes to their creators!
NOTE
If you are in one of these pictures and want it removed, please contact me by email (see about/imprint page).
Slides The slides of the talks can be found here: Ceph Community presentations channel - SlideShare.
Welcome &amp;amp; Kickoff Ceph Day Berlin 2018 - Cloudical team arrived at the conference center I arrived with my colleagues from Cloudical at the Ceph Day Berlin location, which at the same time was the location for OpenStack Summit.</description></item><item><title>What exactly is „Cloud Native" even?</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/What-exactly-is-Cloud-Native-even/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 08:15:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/What-exactly-is-Cloud-Native-even/</guid><description>Checkout the orignal publication of this article on the The Cloud Report site, where it was posted originally, here: The Cloud Report - What exactly is „Cloud Native&amp;quot; even?.
Let’s look at the Cloud Native Computing Foundation mission statement for an explanation what &amp;ldquo;Cloud Native&amp;rdquo; is in their eyes:
The Foundation’s mission is to create and drive the adoption of a new computing paradigm that is optimized for modern distributed systems environments capable of scaling to tens of thousands of self healing multi-tenant nodes.</description></item><item><title>Distributed Storage with Rook Presentation</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/Distributed-Storage-with-Rook-Presentation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 15:50:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/Distributed-Storage-with-Rook-Presentation/</guid><description>Thanks! A thanks to Kim-Norman Sahm from Cloudical for reaching out to me if I wanted to talk about Rook with him. Also thanks to Jared Watts, Tony Allen and the other awesome Rook people for creating the slides for KubeCon Copenhagen 2018, on which we based our slides partially on.
Presentation Kim-Norman Sahm and I created this presentation to show off Rook.io at Container Days Hamburg. The files used in the demo during the presentation can be found here: GitHub galexrt/presentation-distributed-storage-with-rook.</description></item><item><title>Container Days 2018 Hamburg</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/Container-Days-2018-Hamburg/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 08:45:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/Container-Days-2018-Hamburg/</guid><description>Thanks! A thanks and shoutout to Cloudical for allowing me to talk about Rook together with Kim-Norman Sahm. Checkout their Twitter: Cloudical.
Day #0 The speaker party was filled with cool people and a nice atmosphere at StrandPauli.
Container Days 2018 - Night view from StrandPauli Container Days 2018 - Reeperbahn Trainstation sign Obvious visit to the Hamburg Reeperbahn. Just kidding, we just used the train station to get back to our hotel (as far as I remember) ;)</description></item><item><title>GitLab + Kubernetes: Using GitLab CI's Kubernetes Cluster feature</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/GitLab-Kubernetes-Using-GitLab-CIs-Kubernetes-Cluster-feature/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 12:35:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/GitLab-Kubernetes-Using-GitLab-CIs-Kubernetes-Cluster-feature/</guid><description>UPDATED An updated version of this post can be found here: GitLab + Kubernetes: Using GitLab CI&amp;rsquo;s Kubernetes Cluster feature - UPDATED.
Please use it instead of this post which is already a bit dated again and not all uptodate with the latest changes to the example repository. Thanks!
Intro This post walks through using GitLab CI&amp;rsquo;s Kubernetes Cluster feature to deploy built container images to Kubernetes.
This is an update to my old guide which uses the in GitLab 10.</description></item><item><title>k8s-vagrant-multi-node: The magic behind this project</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/k8s-vagrant-multi-node-the-magic-behind-this-project/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 13:12:27 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/k8s-vagrant-multi-node-the-magic-behind-this-project/</guid><description>Kubernetes and Hashicorp Vagrant Logo The GitHub repository can be found here: galexrt/k8s-vagrant-multi-node.
Intro The Vagrant VirtualBox provider can&amp;rsquo;t start VMs in parallel (--parallel flag for vagrant up). It is possible to do so, but you need to &amp;ldquo;invest&amp;rdquo; in Vagrantfile and Makefile.
Solution Use Makefile to run NODE=X vagrant up, where NODE=X is the &amp;ldquo;number&amp;rdquo; of the node you want to be started. To tell Makefile to start these &amp;ldquo;many&amp;rdquo; targets you use a &amp;ldquo;hack&amp;rdquo; like this:</description></item><item><title>My New Home Office Setup</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/My-New-Home-Office-Setup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 13:47:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/My-New-Home-Office-Setup/</guid><description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going over my new game and home office setup.
New table First part of the new home setup, was a new table. The previous was a cheap table from IKEA. The new table is 2.60m long instead of previously only 2.00m. The 0.60m more space is awesome. The desk feels emptier but in a good way, and I have more space for equipment.
If you have the space, go for a big table and keep it clean!</description></item><item><title>KubeCon Copenhagen 2018 - Day 3</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/KubeCon-Copenhagen-2018-Day-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 08:16:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/KubeCon-Copenhagen-2018-Day-3/</guid><description>NOTE All credit for the slides in the pictures goes to their creators!
NOTE If you are in one of these pictures and want it removed, please contact me by email (see about/imprint page).
WIP This post is still work in progress! The content of this post can rapidly change. This note will be removed when the post has been completed. TODO
Proof read. Welcome! A warm &amp;ldquo;Welcome&amp;rdquo; if you are new to the three day post series from KubeCon Copenhagen, I recommend you to checkout the first day blog post too, here KubeCon Copenhagen 2018 Day 1 and the second day blog post, here KubeCon Copenhagen 2018 Day 2.</description></item><item><title>KubeCon Copenhagen 2018 - Day 2</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/KubeCon-Copenhagen-2018-Day-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 08:30:27 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/KubeCon-Copenhagen-2018-Day-2/</guid><description>NOTE
All credit for the slides in the pictures goes to their creators!
NOTE
If you are in one of these pictures and want it removed, please contact me by email (see about/imprint page).
WIP This post is still work in progress! The content of this post can rapidly change. This note will be removed when the post has been completed.
Welcome! A warm &amp;ldquo;Welcome&amp;rdquo; if you are new to the three day post series from KubeCon Copenhagen, I recommend you to checkout the first day blog post too, here KubeCon Copenhagen 2018 Day 1.</description></item><item><title>KubeCon Copenhagen 2018 - Day 1</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/KubeCon-Copenhagen-2018-Day-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 07:45:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/KubeCon-Copenhagen-2018-Day-1/</guid><description>NOTE
All credit for the slides in the pictures goes to their creators!
NOTE
If you are in one of these pictures and want it removed, please contact me by email (see about/imprint page).
WIP This post is still work in progress! The content of this post can rapidly change. This note will be removed when the post has been completed.
Welcome! A big welcome to everyone at KubeCon! I&amp;rsquo;m happy to have already met a good amount of Rooklers just during badge pickup.</description></item><item><title>KubeCon Austin 2017 (Recap) Presentation</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/KubeCon-Austin-2017-Recap-Presentation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 08:30:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/KubeCon-Austin-2017-Recap-Presentation/</guid><description>I created this presentation to recap my visit to KubeCon 2017 in Austin for my colleagues.
If you want to present my slides somewhere, please get in contact with me first. Thanks!
If you have any suggestions for the presentation, feel free to leave them in the comments. :)</description></item><item><title>CRI-O + Container Linux: How to Install</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/CRI-O-Container-Linux-How-to-Install/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 21:14:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/CRI-O-Container-Linux-How-to-Install/</guid><description>Intro WARNING
Currently it is very very far from optimal to run CRI-O on a &amp;ldquo;no package manager&amp;rdquo; system like Container Linux. For curious people, this should work &amp;ldquo;perfectly&amp;rdquo; though.
NOTE
If it is not clear from the above WARNING, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend this for production (yet). Personally I will soon replace Docker with CRI-O in my private Kubernetes cluster though, because Docker causes issues in my cluster.
This post is showing how you can install and run CRI-O for Kubernetes on Container Linux (previously CoreOS).</description></item><item><title>Ceph Day Darmstadt 2018</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/Ceph-Day-Germany-2018/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 06:20:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/Ceph-Day-Germany-2018/</guid><description>NOTE
All credit for the slides in the pictures goes to their creators!
NOTE
If you are in one of these pictures and want it removed, please contact me by email (see about/imprint page).
Welcome &amp;amp; Kickoff On my way to Ceph Day Darmstadt 2018 We got some small sweet breakfast snacks and coffee to start the day off!
Ceph Day Darmstadt 2018 Kickoff Talks Ceph Luminous is out what&amp;rsquo;s in it for you?</description></item><item><title>GitLab: Use Keycloak as SAML 2.0 OmniAuth Provider</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/GitLab-Keycloak-SAML-2-0-OmniAuth-Provider/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 16:15:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/GitLab-Keycloak-SAML-2-0-OmniAuth-Provider/</guid><description>Intro This post shows how you can use Keycloak with SAML 2.0 as an OmniAuth Provider for GitLab (CE and EE). Please note that these settings are tested only with GitLab CE 10.x.x and above. GitLab EE edition should probably work too, additionally offers more control features like Admin groups, &amp;ldquo;User must be in group/role to be able to login&amp;rdquo;, etc.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of Keycloak yet, checkout their website at: Keycloak.</description></item><item><title>KubeCon 2017 Austin</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/KubeCon-2017-Austin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 12:09:28 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/KubeCon-2017-Austin/</guid><description>NOTE All credit for the slides in the pictures goes to their creators!
NOTE If you are in one of these pictures and want it removed, please contact me by email (see about/imprint page).
Thanks! A huge thanks goes out to Rook and Quantum Corporation for helping me with my trip and the conference! Checkout their Twitter @rook_io and @QuantumCorp.
Day #0 NOTE If you don&amp;rsquo;t want to read about my flight and stay, skip to Day #1.</description></item><item><title>Writing your first Golang Microthingy Presentation</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Writing-your-first-Golang-Microthingy-Presentation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 12:15:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Writing-your-first-Golang-Microthingy-Presentation/</guid><description>I created this presentation to talk a bit about Microservices and Goland. In addition for the presentation, there is a repository containing Golang example code for a very basic Microservice example application.
If you want to present my slides somewhere, please get in contact with me first. Thanks!
If you have any suggestions for the presentation, feel free to leave them in the comments. :)</description></item><item><title>GitLab + Kubernetes: GitLab on top of Kubernetes</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/GitLab-Kubernetes-GitLab-on-top-of-Kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 18:00:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/GitLab-Kubernetes-GitLab-on-top-of-Kubernetes/</guid><description>Intro This is the third post in the three post series about Kubernetes and GitLab. The first post can be found here: Edenmal - GitLab + Kubernetes: Perfect Match for Continuous Delivery with Container.
This post will not cover how to setup a Postgres and Redis server/cluster for the GitLab. In the near future I may even publish all my current manifests, that also contain Postgres and Redis server/cluster manifests.</description></item><item><title>Container Linux: Deploy on Bare-Metal without DHCP server</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Container-Linux-Deploy-on-Bare-Metal-without-DHCP-server/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 19:41:04 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Container-Linux-Deploy-on-Bare-Metal-without-DHCP-server/</guid><description>Intro This post shows you how you can run Container Linux without a DHCP server configured for custom iPXE boot.
Clarification Thanks to Baju Judiantara for his comment! He correctly found that the title is contradict to the IPXE boot script in Step 4 - Add grub config for iPXE boot. To resolve the conratdict of the title with the post I have added a snippet which does the interface configuration manual and not over DHCP.</description></item><item><title>GitLab + Kubernetes: Running CI Runners in Kubernetes</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/GitLab-Kubernetes-Running-CI-Runners-in-Kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/GitLab-Kubernetes-Running-CI-Runners-in-Kubernetes/</guid><description>Intro In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll be going over using GitLab CI to create your application&amp;rsquo;s container Continuous Delivery to Kubernetes. This is the second post in the three post series about Kubernetes and GitLab. The first post can be found here: Edenmal - GitLab + Kubernetes: Perfect Match for Continuous Delivery with Container.
NOTE Please check the requirements before beginning.
Requirements Kubernetes cluster Running GitLab instance kubectl binary (with Kubernetes cluster access) StorageClass configured in Kubernetes ReadWriteMany Persistent Storage (example CephFS using Rook) Manifests The manifests shown in this blog post will also be available on GitHub here: GitHub - galexrt/kubernetes-manifests.</description></item><item><title>Ceph: rbd bench Commands</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Ceph-rbd-bench-Commands/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 23:53:35 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Ceph-rbd-bench-Commands/</guid><description>Intro The reference to these commands is from Sébastien Han Blog Post &amp;ldquo;Ceph: validate that the RBD cache is active&amp;rdquo; and the rbd man Page. For more posts about Ceph, take a look at Sébastien Han Blog.
Requisite - RBD image for running the Benchmarks To be able to run a rbd benchmark, you need to create an image. The command to create an image for this would be:
$ RBD_IMAGE_NAME=&amp;#34;bench1&amp;#34; $ rbd create --size=10G $RBD_IMAGE_NAME rbd bench Flags Takes normal rbd command flags like:</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes - WYNTK - GitLab CI + Kubernetes Presentation</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Kubernetes-WYNTK-GitLab-CI-Kubernetes-Presentation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 19:32:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Kubernetes-WYNTK-GitLab-CI-Kubernetes-Presentation/</guid><description>This is a presentation about WYNTK or &amp;ldquo;What You Need To Know&amp;rdquo; about using GitLab CI with Kubernetes for Continous Delivery as a quick overview.
If you want to present my slides somewhere, please get in contact with me first. Thanks!
If you have any suggestions for the presentation, feel free to leave them in the comments. :)</description></item><item><title>GitLab + Kubernetes: Perfect Match for Continuous Delivery with Container</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/GitLab-Kubernetes-Perfect-Match-for-Continuous-Delivery-with-Container/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 17:08:36 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/GitLab-Kubernetes-Perfect-Match-for-Continuous-Delivery-with-Container/</guid><description>Deprecation Warning GitLab has deprecated the Kubernetes integration with release 10.3.
Kubernetes service integration has been deprecated in GitLab 10.3. If the service is active the cluster information still be editable, however we advised to disable and reconfigure the clusters using the new Clusters page. If the service is inactive the fields will be uneditable. Read GitLab 10.3 release post for more information. See https://docs.gitlab.com/ce/user/project/integrations/kubernetes.html.
Instead of the integration, the new GitLab CI Kubernetes Cluster feature should be used, the documentation for that can be found here: https://docs.</description></item><item><title>Container Linux: Specification YAML</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Container-Linux-Specification-YAML/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 16:14:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Container-Linux-Specification-YAML/</guid><description>I checked the Container Linux configuration page and found the config specification here: https://coreos.com/os/docs/latest/configuration.html (link refers to the latest version, the current version can be seen in the below field). But it was presented as a HTML list, which I thought is bad and took it upon me to create a YAML version from it for easy use.
CURRENT VERSION 1451.2.0
The result can be found on GitHub Gist or simply below in the embeded Gist:</description></item><item><title>Google Cloud: Enterprise Grade Hybrid Cloud with Kubernetes Cluster Federation</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Google-Cloud-Enterprise-Grade-Hybrid-Cloud-with-Kubernetes-Cluster-Federation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 09:14:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Google-Cloud-Enterprise-Grade-Hybrid-Cloud-with-Kubernetes-Cluster-Federation/</guid><description>Intro I went to the Google Cloud Event about &amp;ldquo;Enterprise Grade Hybrid Cloud with Kubernetes Cluster Federation&amp;rdquo; at Google Munich.
NOTE I wrote the next few sentences while not having internet connection because of &amp;ldquo;DeutscheBahn&amp;rdquo; ;)
A thing I just have to note is that I had taken an IC instead of an ICE to Munich. Now guess what, ICs don&amp;rsquo;t have wifi.. I personally think that in a county as advanced as Germany, it should be &amp;ldquo;required&amp;rdquo; to have wifi on &amp;ldquo;every&amp;rdquo; train.</description></item><item><title>Container Days 2017 Hamburg</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Container-Days-2017-Hamburg/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 11:23:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Container-Days-2017-Hamburg/</guid><description>Thanks! A huge thanks and shoutout to Max Inden @mxinden for having some time for a very interesting talk.
BTW Checkout CoreOS&amp;rsquo;s awesome Kubernetes prometheus-operator project. It is awesome for easily running Prometheus + Alertmanager in Kubernetes.
Day #1 Let&amp;rsquo;s see what nice things the day will bring. I hope I&amp;rsquo;ll learn something new about containers and Kubernetes, and hopefully meet some new people. :-)
Presentation: &amp;ldquo;A DevOps State of Mind: Continuous Security for Containers with Kubernetes&amp;rdquo; The presentation of Chris van Tuin from Red Hat was very interesting for me.</description></item><item><title>Golang: go get from GitLab</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Golang-go-get-from-Gitlab/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 14:39:01 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Golang-go-get-from-Gitlab/</guid><description>I just now came across the problem that I created a repository on a private GitLab instance for a Golang project and could not just use go get ... to get it. After a short Google search, I came across this StackOverflow question and thankfully it had a working answer.
The original StackOverflow question can be found here: StackOverflow - how do you use golang with a private gitlab repo?, the question was asked by User James Fremen.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes Elasticsearch Operator</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Kubernetes-Elasticsearch-Operator/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 10:51:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Kubernetes-Elasticsearch-Operator/</guid><description>I got the inspiration for writing a so called operator for Kubernetes from the CoreOS project prometheus-operator. So a big thanks to them for creating the project, as also the code is almost completely based on their operator code.
The project can be found on GitHub: https://github.com/galexrt/elasticsearch-operator.
Installation Use the bundle.yaml that is in the repo root, to run the operator on the cluster.
kubectl create -f bundle.yaml Verify the installation of the ThirdPartyResources To verify that the operator has successful installed its ThirdPartyResources, you simply check the Kubernetes server for them:</description></item><item><title>(Old) Docker Presentation</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Docker-Presentation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 09:15:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Docker-Presentation/</guid><description>I created this Docker presentation about three years ago (2014).
NOTE
The presentation is in german.
If you want to present my slides somewhere, please get in contact with me first. Thanks!
If you have any suggestions for the presentation, feel free to leave them in the comments. :)</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes v3 Presentation</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Kubernetes-v3-Presentation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 13:33:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Kubernetes-v3-Presentation/</guid><description>This is an updated version of my Kubernetes v2 presentation.
NOTE
The presentation is in german.
If you want to present my slides somewhere, please get in contact with me first. Thanks!
If you have any suggestions for the presentation, feel free to leave them in the comments. :)</description></item><item><title>My Blog Layout has been updated</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/My-Blog-Layout-has-been-updated/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 13:20:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/My-Blog-Layout-has-been-updated/</guid><description>I finally had some time to add Google Custom Search Engine to my Blog.
I fixed some layout bugs with Bootstrap wells too. Some well-classes were placed at the wrong level making some of them look bigger than others when viewing the page from mobile.
My fork of XadillaX/hexadillax Hexo theme is located at galexrt/hexadillax.</description></item><item><title>iptables: Using statistic module</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/iptables-Using-statistic-module/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 15:50:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/iptables-Using-statistic-module/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Load Balance&amp;rdquo; with iptables between two servers Kubernetes uses this method to load balance traffic between pods in the cluster.
The commands below create separate chains for each server and for the load balancing of port 80 in this case:
iptables -t nat -N LB_PORT80 iptables -t nat -N LB_PORT80_SERVER1 iptables -t nat -A LB_PORT80 \ -m statistic --mode random --probability 0.5000 \ -j LB_PORT80_SERVER1 iptables -t nat -N LB_PORT80_SERVER2 iptables -t nat -A LB_PORT80 \ -j LB_PORT80_SERVER2 iptables -t nat -A INPUT -p tcp -m tcp --dport 80 -j LB_PORT80 Dropping packages with a X% probability from a specific IP address My favorite rule to mess with people ;)</description></item><item><title>Zulip: Installation</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Zulip-Installation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 09:23:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Zulip-Installation/</guid><description>Please note: This post is more of a &amp;ldquo;draft&amp;rdquo; that may not be on my level of post quality.
Zulip is a powerful open source group chat able to handle multi channel communications. It runs on python.
Requirements An Ubuntu Server with at least 2GB of RAM (2GB RAM is currently the recommended amount for a small site). My example server for this tutorial has the following address:
203.0.113.1 zulip-tutorial-example Preparing your server for Zulip NOTE</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes Interactive Bootcamp</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Kubernetes-Interactive-Bootcamp/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 15:31:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Kubernetes-Interactive-Bootcamp/</guid><description>I just found out that Kubernetes has an interactive bootcamp available.
Here is the link to it: Kubernetes Bootcamp.
The GitHub repo of it is located here.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes v2 Presentation</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Kubernetes-v2-Presentation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 11:35:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Kubernetes-v2-Presentation/</guid><description>I have update my old Kubernetes presentation to contain the latest Kubernetes features.
NOTE
The presentation is in german.
If you want to present my slides somewhere, please get in contact with me first. Thanks!
If you have any suggestions for the presentation, feel free to leave them in the comments. :)</description></item><item><title>Docker: Live restore option for containers</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Docker-Live-restore-option-for-containers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 16:09:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Docker-Live-restore-option-for-containers/</guid><description>Docker 1.12 has a nice set of improvements that significantly improve the ability to administrate the Docker daemon. https://t.co/bXt4PwPXRr
&amp;mdash; Kelsey Hightower (@kelseyhightower) 31. Juli 2016 On the Docker GitHub release/changelog page of v1.12.0 under the Runtime section the first point:
Add &amp;ndash;live-restore daemon flag to keep containers running when daemon shuts down, and regain control on startup #23213
This new option allows containers to keep running even when stopping, restarting or upgrading the Docker daemon.</description></item><item><title>OpenVSwitch: Persistent IP configuration under Rhel based distros</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/OpenVSwitch-Persistent-IP-configuration-under-Rhel-based-distros/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 18:22:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/OpenVSwitch-Persistent-IP-configuration-under-Rhel-based-distros/</guid><description>NOTE
This post is a follow up on my post OpenVSwitch: Multi-Host Overlay Network. The interface in this example is named br0. Change according to your interface.
Preparing for using the interface configurations To persist the configurations you can either use the NetworkManager or use good old network-scripts. Here I&amp;rsquo;m going to show how it&amp;rsquo;s done using the good old network-scripts. First at all we have to disable the NetworkManager service with this command:</description></item><item><title>OpenVSwitch: Multi-Host Overlay Network</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/OpenVSwitch-Multi-Host-Overlay-Network/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 09:25:51 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/OpenVSwitch-Multi-Host-Overlay-Network/</guid><description>NOTE
This tutorial is written for Fedora but can be applied to all rhel based systems. The only &amp;ldquo;big&amp;rdquo; thing you would need to change is the package manager command from dnf to for example yum.
What is OpenVSwitch OpenVSwitch is a SDN application (Software defined networking) that allows you to create networks and switches on software level.
Requirements At least two servers running Fedora 23 or higher (it may even work with Fedora 21 and higher, but it is not tested!</description></item><item><title>Ceph: Build your own cluster on CentOS</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Ceph-Build-your-own-cluster-on-CentOS/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 09:29:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Ceph-Build-your-own-cluster-on-CentOS/</guid><description>Ceph is an object, a block and filesystem storage system.
As you can see from the Ceph.com visitors map here, people all around the world search for it. You can also see some metrics about the Ceph project at their metrics site here.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to go over the installation of a two node Ceph storage cluster. You can then build on those storage nodes and choose multiple storage types you want to use.</description></item><item><title>SteamCMD: Not working on CephFS</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/SteamCMD-Not-working-on-CephFS/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 18:30:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/SteamCMD-Not-working-on-CephFS/</guid><description>See title.
Yes, you read right. SteamCMD is not working on CephFS (and maybe GlusterFS too, I can&amp;rsquo;t test it on GlusterFS ). The reason for that is a &amp;ldquo;failing&amp;rdquo; getdents when on the CephFS. A colleague told me that error may be related to the st_size and the rbytes of CephFS.
strace on xfs filesystem:
[...] [pid 123] stat64(&amp;#34;./zip0.zip&amp;#34;, 0xf71c9c40) = -1 ENOENT (No such file or directory) [pid 123] open(&amp;#34;.</description></item><item><title>Nuclear Fusion Presentation</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Nuclear-Fusion-Presentation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 16:44:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Nuclear-Fusion-Presentation/</guid><description>NOTE
The presentation is in german.
If you want to use or present my presentation somewhere, please get in contact with me first. Thanks!
And for the laughs, my origianl presentation I did for school some years ago and that &amp;ldquo;inspired&amp;rdquo; the new presentation:
If you like or have any suggestions for the presentation, feel free to leave them in the comments. :)</description></item><item><title>PSA: Keep your computer clean!</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/PSA-Keep-your-computer-clean/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 10:43:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/PSA-Keep-your-computer-clean/</guid><description>That much dust came off the radiator. The dust was heavily reducing the cooling of the cpu.
I can&amp;rsquo;t stress this enough. Cooling systems full with dust reducing the cooling throughput your computer.
What do the Pictures &amp;ldquo;tell&amp;rdquo; you? The air flow isn&amp;rsquo;t going through very well. If your computer is under high load, it could happen that the cpu or gpu are throttled. because of high temperature.
In worst case: When it&amp;rsquo;s getting really hot, one of your computer components may overheat and causes your computer to get slower or just turn off.</description></item><item><title>Ansible User Management Role</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Ansible-User-Management-Role/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 14:36:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Ansible-User-Management-Role/</guid><description>GitHub repository: galexrt/ansible-usersmgt. Ansible Galaxy: here
This is an Ansible role for user management that I have created. Currently has the following features:
SSH key management (currently fixed ssh key directory /etc/ssh/authorized_keys, is on the roadmap). Creation and removal of: Groups Users Additional fine tunning through only_on_hosts and not_on_hosts lists possible. Examples This is the EXAMPLES.md from the repository.
If you have any feedback or ideas for improvements, feel free to leave it in the comments or create an issue or pull request on GitHub.</description></item><item><title>In search of a Webhosting</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/In-search-of-a-webhosting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 14:48:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/In-search-of-a-webhosting/</guid><description>Some points you should consider before buying a shared webhosting.
Points to consider about a shared hosting IPv6 connectivity If the hoster offers CloudFlare CDN with the package, you can ignore this point as CloudFlare has 6to4 support.
I personally completely ignore this point, if CloudFlare CDN is available.
Is Unlimited really Unlimited? Some hoster have offers like &amp;ldquo;Unlimited Webspace&amp;rdquo;, but you will never have unlimited space. If you check the disk space with a script, you&amp;rsquo;ll see that you don&amp;rsquo;t have &amp;ldquo;unlimited&amp;rdquo; space.</description></item><item><title>SRCDS Server Restarter Script</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/SRCDS-Server-Restarter-Script/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 15:41:02 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/SRCDS-Server-Restarter-Script/</guid><description>The script uses the Net::SRCDS::Queries Perl module by Author MASANORIH to communicate with the SRCDS servers.
It checks if the servers responds to Source Server Queries, when the server does not respond to the queries, the script considers the server as unreachable/offline. When the server is considered unreachable/offline, the script uses normal bash commands to write a line with unreachable into a file. After the script wrote the line to the file it checks how many lines with unreachable have been written to the file.</description></item><item><title>Docker for Admins Workshop Recap Presentation</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Docker-for-Admins-Workshop-Recap-Presentation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 17:24:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Docker-for-Admins-Workshop-Recap-Presentation/</guid><description>I created the presentation after I held my Docker for Admins Workshop. This presentation is just a small recap of the Workshop and as the Workshop is posted on my blog, I&amp;rsquo;m posting the presentation here too.
If you want to present my slides somewhere, please get in contact with me first. Thanks!
If you like or have any suggestions for the presentation, feel free to leave them in the comments.</description></item><item><title>Docker for Admins - Workshop v2</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Docker-for-Admins-Workshop-v2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 15:48:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Docker-for-Admins-Workshop-v2/</guid><description>Goal of the Workshop The workshop is going to show how simple it is to use Docker and why it is worth a thought to implement it into your development workflow. The second topic is how to compose containers with docker-compose. The last part is about the container orchestration tool Kubernetes by Google. As part of this you are going to create a Kubernetes cluster and you take a look at the internal services of Kubernetes and deploy applications on top of it.</description></item><item><title>ASCII Link Dump</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/ASCII-Link-Dump/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 19:29:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/ASCII-Link-Dump/</guid><description>ASCII Editors ASCIIFlow Infinity (http://asciiflow.com), Developed by Lewis, Designed by Sam and Ryan The old ASCIIFlow on AppSpot ASCII Generators Text to ASCII Art Generator (TAAG) by patorjk.com ASCII Signature by kammerl.de ASCII Generator by network-science.de Image to ASCII PicASCII</description></item><item><title>Docker for Admins - Workshop</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Docker-for-Admins-Workshop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 14:39:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Docker-for-Admins-Workshop/</guid><description>This workshop is deprecated! Please use the new version of the &amp;ldquo;Docker for Admins&amp;rdquo; Workshop post, here.
Goal of the Workshop The Goal is to show how easy it is to use Docker. The simpleness in creating an image for an own project/application. If there&amp;rsquo;s enough time, we also look at how to orchestrate a Kubernetes cluster and let the first containers run on the cluster.
Heads up - &amp;ldquo;Blogger&amp;rdquo; Words Grey Boxes with green line on the left: Mostly contain an useful tip, expected command output or something funny.</description></item><item><title>Online Courses! Online Courses Everywhere!</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Online-Courses-Courses-everywhere/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 21:50:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Online-Courses-Courses-everywhere/</guid><description>Image made using the Imgur Meme Generator.
In the future I&amp;rsquo;m going to add more online course sites.
edX - Free online courses from the world&amp;rsquo;s best universities FutureLearn Courses</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes v1 Presentation</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Kubernetes-v1-Presentation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 15:15:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/Kubernetes-v1-Presentation/</guid><description>I created this Kubernetes presentation last year in september and I think it&amp;rsquo;s worth sharing it here on my blog.
NOTE
The presentation is in german.
If you want to present my slides somewhere, please get in contact with me first. Thanks!
If you have any suggestions for the presentation, feel free to leave them in the comments. :)</description></item><item><title>First Post</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/First-Post/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2016/First-Post/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m posting about linux server administration, Docker, Kubernetes and other suff.
Stay tuned for more! :)</description></item><item><title>Events Archive</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/events/archive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/events/archive/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Impressum</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/site-notice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/site-notice/</guid><description>The Privacy Policy / Datenschutz­erklärung can be found here: Privacy Policy / Datenschutz­erklärung page.
German version of the Site Notice / Impressum below.
Site Notice Information pursuant to Sect. 5 German Telemedia Act (TMG) Alexander Trost
Postfach 11
75196 Kämpfelbach
Germany Contact E-mail: me@galexrt.moe Responsible for the content according to Sect. 55, paragraph 2 RStV Alexander Trost
Postfach 11
75196 Kämpfelbach
Germany Liability for Contents As service providers, we are liable for own contents of these websites according to Paragraph 7, Sect.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/privacy-policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/privacy-policy/</guid><description>The Site Notice / Impressum can be found here: Site Notice / Impressum page.
German version of the Privacy Policy / Datenschutzerklärung below.
Privacy Policy 1. An overview of data protection General information The following information will provide you with an easy to navigate overview of what will happen with your personal data when you visit this website. The term “personal data” comprises all data that can be used to personally identify you.</description></item></channel></rss>