<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Conferences on Edenmal</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/tags/Conferences/</link><description>Recent content in Conferences on Edenmal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© This page/post is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License, please give source if you wish to quote or reproduce.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 19:06:12 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://edenmal.moe/tags/Conferences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FOSDEM'20 Brussels</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2020/FOSDEM20/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 19:06:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2020/FOSDEM20/</guid><description>Checkout the original publication of this article on the The Cloud Report site, where it was posted originally, here: The Cloud Report - FOSDEM’2020 Brussels.
Thanks to The Cloud Report for allowing me to write and publish the post on their blog!
I&amp;rsquo;m sitting in the ICE train back home from FOSDEM'2020 Brussels, and I’ve got only one thing to say: &amp;ldquo;What a wonderful weekend!&amp;rdquo;
FOSDEM, a weekend in Brussles, Belgium, where great minds in the form of developers, administrators and engineers meet and connect.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM'19 Brussels</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/FOSDEM19-Brussels/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 17:50:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/FOSDEM19-Brussels/</guid><description>FOSDEM was from Saturday, 02.02. to Sunday, 03.02.2019 in Brussels, Belgium.
Saturday FOSDEM&amp;#39;19 Brussels - Snow on Saturday FOSDEM&amp;#39;19 Brussels - ULB FOSDEM middle &amp;#39;street&amp;#39; with food trucks FOSDEM&amp;#39;19 Brussels - Booth area FOSDEM&amp;#39;19 Brussels - Gluster, Ceph and Rook booth FOSDEM&amp;#39;19 Brussels - openSUSE Original &amp;#39;Tumbleweed&amp;#39; Beer Extra The Belgian know how to make freaking awesome waffles! LOOK AT THOSE WAFFLES!!!
FOSDEM&amp;#39;19 Brussels - Le Funambule Waffle Selection If you are in Brussels, go to Le Funambule in the inner city of Brussels:</description></item><item><title>Ceph Day Berlin 2018</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/Ceph-Day-Berlin-2018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 08:00:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/Ceph-Day-Berlin-2018/</guid><description>NOTE
All credit for the slides in the pictures goes to their creators!
NOTE
If you are in one of these pictures and want it removed, please contact me by email (see about/imprint page).
Slides The slides of the talks can be found here: Ceph Community presentations channel - SlideShare.
Welcome &amp;amp; Kickoff Ceph Day Berlin 2018 - Cloudical team arrived at the conference center I arrived with my colleagues from Cloudical at the Ceph Day Berlin location, which at the same time was the location for OpenStack Summit.</description></item><item><title>Container Days 2018 Hamburg</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/Container-Days-2018-Hamburg/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 08:45:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/Container-Days-2018-Hamburg/</guid><description>Thanks! A thanks and shoutout to Cloudical for allowing me to talk about Rook together with Kim-Norman Sahm. Checkout their Twitter: Cloudical.
Day #0 The speaker party was filled with cool people and a nice atmosphere at StrandPauli.
Container Days 2018 - Night view from StrandPauli Container Days 2018 - Reeperbahn Trainstation sign Obvious visit to the Hamburg Reeperbahn. Just kidding, we just used the train station to get back to our hotel (as far as I remember) ;)</description></item><item><title>KubeCon Copenhagen 2018 - Day 3</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/KubeCon-Copenhagen-2018-Day-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 08:16:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/KubeCon-Copenhagen-2018-Day-3/</guid><description>NOTE All credit for the slides in the pictures goes to their creators!
NOTE If you are in one of these pictures and want it removed, please contact me by email (see about/imprint page).
WIP This post is still work in progress! The content of this post can rapidly change. This note will be removed when the post has been completed. TODO
Proof read. Welcome! A warm &amp;ldquo;Welcome&amp;rdquo; if you are new to the three day post series from KubeCon Copenhagen, I recommend you to checkout the first day blog post too, here KubeCon Copenhagen 2018 Day 1 and the second day blog post, here KubeCon Copenhagen 2018 Day 2.</description></item><item><title>KubeCon Copenhagen 2018 - Day 2</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/KubeCon-Copenhagen-2018-Day-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 08:30:27 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/KubeCon-Copenhagen-2018-Day-2/</guid><description>NOTE
All credit for the slides in the pictures goes to their creators!
NOTE
If you are in one of these pictures and want it removed, please contact me by email (see about/imprint page).
WIP This post is still work in progress! The content of this post can rapidly change. This note will be removed when the post has been completed.
Welcome! A warm &amp;ldquo;Welcome&amp;rdquo; if you are new to the three day post series from KubeCon Copenhagen, I recommend you to checkout the first day blog post too, here KubeCon Copenhagen 2018 Day 1.</description></item><item><title>KubeCon Copenhagen 2018 - Day 1</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/KubeCon-Copenhagen-2018-Day-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 07:45:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/KubeCon-Copenhagen-2018-Day-1/</guid><description>NOTE
All credit for the slides in the pictures goes to their creators!
NOTE
If you are in one of these pictures and want it removed, please contact me by email (see about/imprint page).
WIP This post is still work in progress! The content of this post can rapidly change. This note will be removed when the post has been completed.
Welcome! A big welcome to everyone at KubeCon! I&amp;rsquo;m happy to have already met a good amount of Rooklers just during badge pickup.</description></item><item><title>Ceph Day Darmstadt 2018</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/Ceph-Day-Germany-2018/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 06:20:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/Ceph-Day-Germany-2018/</guid><description>NOTE
All credit for the slides in the pictures goes to their creators!
NOTE
If you are in one of these pictures and want it removed, please contact me by email (see about/imprint page).
Welcome &amp;amp; Kickoff On my way to Ceph Day Darmstadt 2018 We got some small sweet breakfast snacks and coffee to start the day off!
Ceph Day Darmstadt 2018 Kickoff Talks Ceph Luminous is out what&amp;rsquo;s in it for you?</description></item><item><title>KubeCon 2017 Austin</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/KubeCon-2017-Austin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 12:09:28 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/KubeCon-2017-Austin/</guid><description>NOTE All credit for the slides in the pictures goes to their creators!
NOTE If you are in one of these pictures and want it removed, please contact me by email (see about/imprint page).
Thanks! A huge thanks goes out to Rook and Quantum Corporation for helping me with my trip and the conference! Checkout their Twitter @rook_io and @QuantumCorp.
Day #0 NOTE If you don&amp;rsquo;t want to read about my flight and stay, skip to Day #1.</description></item><item><title>Container Days 2017 Hamburg</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Container-Days-2017-Hamburg/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 11:23:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Container-Days-2017-Hamburg/</guid><description>Thanks! A huge thanks and shoutout to Max Inden @mxinden for having some time for a very interesting talk.
BTW Checkout CoreOS&amp;rsquo;s awesome Kubernetes prometheus-operator project. It is awesome for easily running Prometheus + Alertmanager in Kubernetes.
Day #1 Let&amp;rsquo;s see what nice things the day will bring. I hope I&amp;rsquo;ll learn something new about containers and Kubernetes, and hopefully meet some new people. :-)
Presentation: &amp;ldquo;A DevOps State of Mind: Continuous Security for Containers with Kubernetes&amp;rdquo; The presentation of Chris van Tuin from Red Hat was very interesting for me.</description></item></channel></rss>