<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Container Linux on Edenmal</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/tags/Container-Linux/</link><description>Recent content in Container Linux on Edenmal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© This page/post is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License, please give source if you wish to quote or reproduce.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 21:14:11 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://edenmal.moe/tags/Container-Linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CRI-O + Container Linux: How to Install</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/CRI-O-Container-Linux-How-to-Install/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 21:14:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/CRI-O-Container-Linux-How-to-Install/</guid><description>Intro WARNING
Currently it is very very far from optimal to run CRI-O on a &amp;ldquo;no package manager&amp;rdquo; system like Container Linux. For curious people, this should work &amp;ldquo;perfectly&amp;rdquo; though.
NOTE
If it is not clear from the above WARNING, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend this for production (yet). Personally I will soon replace Docker with CRI-O in my private Kubernetes cluster though, because Docker causes issues in my cluster.
This post is showing how you can install and run CRI-O for Kubernetes on Container Linux (previously CoreOS).</description></item><item><title>Container Linux: Deploy on Bare-Metal without DHCP server</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Container-Linux-Deploy-on-Bare-Metal-without-DHCP-server/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 19:41:04 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Container-Linux-Deploy-on-Bare-Metal-without-DHCP-server/</guid><description>Intro This post shows you how you can run Container Linux without a DHCP server configured for custom iPXE boot.
Clarification Thanks to Baju Judiantara for his comment! He correctly found that the title is contradict to the IPXE boot script in Step 4 - Add grub config for iPXE boot. To resolve the conratdict of the title with the post I have added a snippet which does the interface configuration manual and not over DHCP.</description></item><item><title>Container Linux: Specification YAML</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Container-Linux-Specification-YAML/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 16:14:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Container-Linux-Specification-YAML/</guid><description>I checked the Container Linux configuration page and found the config specification here: https://coreos.com/os/docs/latest/configuration.html (link refers to the latest version, the current version can be seen in the below field). But it was presented as a HTML list, which I thought is bad and took it upon me to create a YAML version from it for easy use.
CURRENT VERSION 1451.2.0
The result can be found on GitHub Gist or simply below in the embeded Gist:</description></item></channel></rss>