<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rook on Edenmal</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/tags/Rook/</link><description>Recent content in Rook on Edenmal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© This page/post is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License, please give source if you wish to quote or reproduce.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 19:06:12 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://edenmal.moe/tags/Rook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FOSDEM'20 Brussels</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2020/FOSDEM20/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 19:06:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2020/FOSDEM20/</guid><description>Checkout the original publication of this article on the The Cloud Report site, where it was posted originally, here: The Cloud Report - FOSDEM’2020 Brussels.
Thanks to The Cloud Report for allowing me to write and publish the post on their blog!
I&amp;rsquo;m sitting in the ICE train back home from FOSDEM'2020 Brussels, and I’ve got only one thing to say: &amp;ldquo;What a wonderful weekend!&amp;rdquo;
FOSDEM, a weekend in Brussles, Belgium, where great minds in the form of developers, administrators and engineers meet and connect.</description></item><item><title>Rook: New Winds in the v1.1 release</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2020/Rook-New-Winds-in-the-v1-1-release/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 15:20:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2020/Rook-New-Winds-in-the-v1-1-release/</guid><description>This is a cross post of an older post from The Cloud Report, be sure to checkout the The Cloud Report website.
Thanks to them for allowing me to write and publish the post on their blog!
Preface Rook is a storage orchestrator for Kubernetes using the operator pattern. That means that Rook can run, e.g., Ceph, EdgeFS, Yugabyte and other persistence providers in a Kubernetes cluster. This allows applications to create, e.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM'19 Brussels</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/FOSDEM19-Brussels/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 17:50:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/FOSDEM19-Brussels/</guid><description>FOSDEM was from Saturday, 02.02. to Sunday, 03.02.2019 in Brussels, Belgium.
Saturday FOSDEM&amp;#39;19 Brussels - Snow on Saturday FOSDEM&amp;#39;19 Brussels - ULB FOSDEM middle &amp;#39;street&amp;#39; with food trucks FOSDEM&amp;#39;19 Brussels - Booth area FOSDEM&amp;#39;19 Brussels - Gluster, Ceph and Rook booth FOSDEM&amp;#39;19 Brussels - openSUSE Original &amp;#39;Tumbleweed&amp;#39; Beer Extra The Belgian know how to make freaking awesome waffles! LOOK AT THOSE WAFFLES!!!
FOSDEM&amp;#39;19 Brussels - Le Funambule Waffle Selection If you are in Brussels, go to Le Funambule in the inner city of Brussels:</description></item><item><title>Rook more than Ceph</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Rook-more-than-Ceph/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 08:13:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Rook-more-than-Ceph/</guid><description>Checkout the orignal publication of this article on the The Cloud Report site here: The Cloud Report - Rook more than Ceph.
Preface Rook allows you to run Ceph and other storage backends in Kubernetes with ease. Consumption of storage, especially block and filesystem storage, can be consumed through Kubernetes native ways. this allows users of a Kubernetes cluster to consume storage easily as in &amp;ldquo;any&amp;rdquo; other standard Kubernetes cluster out there.</description></item></channel></rss>