<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ContainerDays on Edenmal</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/tags/ContainerDays/</link><description>Recent content in ContainerDays on Edenmal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© This page/post is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License, please give source if you wish to quote or reproduce.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 20:23:04 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://edenmal.moe/tags/ContainerDays/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sitrep Container and IPv6 Presentation</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Sitrep-Container-and-IPv6-Presentation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 20:23:04 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Sitrep-Container-and-IPv6-Presentation/</guid><description>I created this presentation for a local IPv6 &amp;ldquo;Stammtisch&amp;rdquo; to talk about the current situation of IPv6 in Docker and Kubernetes.
If you want to present these slides somewhere, please get in contact with me first. Thanks!
If you have any suggestions for the presentation, feel free to leave them in the comments.</description></item><item><title>Importance of IPv6 in a Cloudy World Presentation</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Importance-of-IPv6-in-a-cloudy-World-Presentation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 12:50:19 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Importance-of-IPv6-in-a-cloudy-World-Presentation/</guid><description>I created this presentation to show off why IPv6 is important in the current day and age of Cloud at Container Days Hamburg.
If you want to present these slides somewhere, please get in contact with me first. Thanks!
If you have any suggestions for the presentation, feel free to leave them in the comments.
Recording The recording of the talk can be found on Container Days YouTube channel:
Impressions Good morning #containerdays</description></item><item><title>Container Days 2018 Hamburg</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/Container-Days-2018-Hamburg/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 08:45:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2018/Container-Days-2018-Hamburg/</guid><description>Thanks! A thanks and shoutout to Cloudical for allowing me to talk about Rook together with Kim-Norman Sahm. Checkout their Twitter: Cloudical.
Day #0 The speaker party was filled with cool people and a nice atmosphere at StrandPauli.
Container Days 2018 - Night view from StrandPauli Container Days 2018 - Reeperbahn Trainstation sign Obvious visit to the Hamburg Reeperbahn. Just kidding, we just used the train station to get back to our hotel (as far as I remember) ;)</description></item><item><title>Container Days 2017 Hamburg</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Container-Days-2017-Hamburg/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 11:23:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2017/Container-Days-2017-Hamburg/</guid><description>Thanks! A huge thanks and shoutout to Max Inden @mxinden for having some time for a very interesting talk.
BTW Checkout CoreOS&amp;rsquo;s awesome Kubernetes prometheus-operator project. It is awesome for easily running Prometheus + Alertmanager in Kubernetes.
Day #1 Let&amp;rsquo;s see what nice things the day will bring. I hope I&amp;rsquo;ll learn something new about containers and Kubernetes, and hopefully meet some new people. :-)
Presentation: &amp;ldquo;A DevOps State of Mind: Continuous Security for Containers with Kubernetes&amp;rdquo; The presentation of Chris van Tuin from Red Hat was very interesting for me.</description></item></channel></rss>