<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Network on Edenmal</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/tags/Network/</link><description>Recent content in Network on Edenmal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© This page/post is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License, please give source if you wish to quote or reproduce.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 11:58:26 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://edenmal.moe/tags/Network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Home Office Setup v2</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2020/My-Home-Office-Setup-v2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 11:58:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2020/My-Home-Office-Setup-v2/</guid><description>It was time Time to create an updated post of my improved home office setup. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive right into it.
Table The table is 1.60m (~5.24934 feet) long.
The cable management has been improved in comparsion to my previous setup post. It can still be further improved but it is much better than before and I&amp;rsquo;m finally happy with it now.
Table / Desk Shot Computers Gaming This compliments my &amp;ldquo;small&amp;rdquo; Steam library pretty well and the Valve Index headset which is pretty dope to use and play games on.</description></item><item><title>Ancientt - Automation for Network Testing Tools</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Ancientt-Automation-for-Network-Testing-Tools/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 13:10:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Ancientt-Automation-for-Network-Testing-Tools/</guid><description>This is a cross post from The Cloud Report. Be sure to checkout the The Cloud Report website.
What is Ancientt Ancientt is a tool to automate network testing tools, like iperf3, in dynamic environments such as Kubernetes, Ansible and more to come dynamic environments.
Meaning that, if you want to test the network throughput with iperf3 of your Kubernetes cluster, you can easily do that with Ancientt. A simple &amp;ldquo;test definitions&amp;rdquo; file is used to tell Ancientt what exactly to do:</description></item><item><title>Sitrep Container and IPv6 Presentation</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Sitrep-Container-and-IPv6-Presentation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 20:23:04 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Sitrep-Container-and-IPv6-Presentation/</guid><description>I created this presentation for a local IPv6 &amp;ldquo;Stammtisch&amp;rdquo; to talk about the current situation of IPv6 in Docker and Kubernetes.
If you want to present these slides somewhere, please get in contact with me first. Thanks!
If you have any suggestions for the presentation, feel free to leave them in the comments.</description></item><item><title>Importance of IPv6 in a Cloudy World Presentation</title><link>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Importance-of-IPv6-in-a-cloudy-World-Presentation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 12:50:19 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://edenmal.moe/post/2019/Importance-of-IPv6-in-a-cloudy-World-Presentation/</guid><description>I created this presentation to show off why IPv6 is important in the current day and age of Cloud at Container Days Hamburg.
If you want to present these slides somewhere, please get in contact with me first. Thanks!
If you have any suggestions for the presentation, feel free to leave them in the comments.
Recording The recording of the talk can be found on Container Days YouTube channel:
Impressions Good morning #containerdays</description></item></channel></rss>